Watch out!
George of the Jungle is a adventure, comedy,
family film directed by Sam Weisman.
Deep in the African jungle, a baby named George, the sole
survivor of a plane crash, is raised by gorillas.
George grows up to be a buff and lovable klutz who has a rainforest full of animal friends: Tookie, his big-beaked
toucan messenger; Ape, a witty talking gorilla; and Shep, a peanut-loving pooch of an elephant.
But when poachers mess with George's pals, the King of Swing swings into action.
George of the Jungle, played by Brendan Fraser.
Ursula Stanhope, played by Leslie Mann.
Lyle Van de Groot, played by Thomas Haden Church.
An Ape Named 'Ape' (voice), played by John Cleese.
Kwame, played by Richard Roundtree.
Thor, played by Abraham Benrubi.
George of the Jungle is a 1997 American comedy film directed by Sam Weisman.
It is based on the 1967 American animated television series of the same name created by Jay Ward and
Bill Scott, which parodied the fictional character Tarzan by Edgar Rice Burroughs.
The screenplay was written by Dana Olsen and Audrey Wells.
The film stars Brendan Fraser as the title character, alongside Leslie Mann, Thomas
Haden Church, Holland Taylor, Richard Roundtree, and John Cleese.
The plot follows a man who was raised by animals in the jungle and later falls in love
with a wealthy heiress, leading to conflict with her self-absorbed fiancé.
Produced by Walt Disney Pictures, the film was released theatrically
in the United States and Canada on July 16, 1997.
It premiered on the Disney Channel in the United States on December 5, 1998.
The film received mixed reviews from critics but was a
commercial success grossing $174 million worldwide.
A direct-to-video sequel, George of the Jungle 2,
was released on October 21, 2003.
The film explores themes of san francisco,
california, africa, gorilla, narration, lion.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.